Georgia Hobson

Web Developer and Marketer

Location: Birmingham UK, CV36 5JT Contacts: Phone: 07947128426 Email: ghobs987@gmail.com

Socials: LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/georgia-hobson-b48434150 GitHub: https://github.com/G-bot987

Portfolio: https://g-bot987.github.io/portfolio/#

Summary

Full stack web developer with a background in Marketing and extensive client handling experience. My drive and intrigue for coding inspired me to achieve an A- certificate in web development through the University of Birmingham. Experience using; React.js, Node.js, JavaScript, MySQL, MongoDB, Git, Command Line, JQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, Express.js, HTML5.

Ambition and drive to be successful in web development ensured successful completion of this course while retaining full time employment. This experience in client facing industries, most recently while working from home has required discipline and strong time management. Evidenced by an exceptional quality assurance score and attendance record. Coupled with recent success at Birmingham and marketing acumen that makes for a user focused results driven developer looking forward to taking advantage of opportunities both domestically and internationally that will see me add specificity and nuance to my code.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Node.JS, React.JS, MongoDB, Command Line, CSS, HTML5, JQuery, Bootstrap, Express.JS

Projects

Tech-Blog

Source Code: https://github.com/G-bot987/TechBlog **Deployed:** https://dry-eyrie-85153.herokuapp.com/

Summary: A full stack application, that allows users to log in, create posts, amend them and comment on other users posts. The platform is designed to allow tech enthusiast to reach out to others to either provide assistance or ask for it. Future developments will include more social functionality for networking and staying in contact.

Technologies: JavaScript, Sequelize, MySql, Moment, Express Handlebars, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS

Employee Manager

Source Code: https://github.com/G-bot987/employee-manager-29.08.21

Demo Video: https://drive.google.com/file/d/16ZVj7zfFe_IYRHH2Utjb4Rl4dU076VWi/view

Summary: Command Line application that can generate individual and team profiles allowing easy access to key info. This concise applications primary benefit is its time saving functionality, the ability to quickly add and remove team members and saving key info for easy future access is perfect for integration with HR and employee management software.

Technologies: JavaScript, Node.JS, HTML.

Mind GJM

Source Code: https://github.com/G-bot987/inQuizitive

Deployed: https://uk-inquizitive.herokuapp.com/

Summary: A group project that allows users to create an account, design quizzes, take quizzes. The motivation behind this platform, was to improve connectivity to otherwise disparate community of pub quiz gamers who have lost the ability to interact with each other as a result of Covid 19. Mind GJM provides a user friendly UI for pub quizzes existing functionality will save scores and track progress.

Role: Developer responsible for quiz search, update and profile functionality.

Technologies: Node.js, GraphQL, MongoDB, JavaScript, React, Express.JS, Bootstrap, Tailwind.

Experience

Caller Handler From: July 2021- Present Based: Remote

Government Department

• diligence in digesting government policy meant I thrived in a rapidly changing environment. his saw me rank in the top100 across KPI's for December.

• consistently achieved "amazing" quality assurance through adopting an empathetic and pedagogical approach.

Customer Advisor From: May 2021- July 2021 Based: Banbury, Oxfordshire

Marks And Spencer PLC

 Manual speed and attention to detail saw me achieve KPI's in a fast paced business.

Domiciliary Care Worker From: June 2020 - May 2021 Based: Multiple

Helping Hands

• Patience and communication saw me ensure a high quality of life for those with complex medical and mental health needs who struggled the most during the pandemic.

Manager From: Oct 2014 - September 2016 Based: Liverpool St, London

Eye Contact Opticians

• Through the implementation of innovative technology order delivery time was improved by 10% and monthly expenses reduced by 5%.

• excellent communication drove learning and development resulting in improved team performance leading to record personal(70,000) and business sales(150,000).

Education

Birmingham University Achieved: December 2021

A- Certificate In Web Development

Salford University Achieved: July 2019

2:1 BSc Marketing

Notable Achievements

Recognition

Nominated for optical consultant of the year 2015

Persistence and Work Ethic

completing my degree without any of my extra time allowance for dyslexia and graduating with 3 lanaguages: Arabic, Mandarin, Spanish